FABJOLA KASAJ

(925)-758-8902 | fkasaj@horizon.csueastbay.edu | https://github.com/fabjolakasaj

OBJECTIVE:

A highly analytical individual with three years of experience as a business analyst. Looking to obtain a Data Analyst position, to utilize my prior experience. Offering expertise in developing/implementing the software in new clients and analyzing large complex and multi-dimensional data set using a variety of tools like Python, SQL, and R.

EDUCATION:

California State University - East Bay, Hayward, CA Master of Science in Business Analytics	01/2020 - Present
University of Tirana — Tirana, Albania Master of Science in Accounting and Auditing	10/2014 - 07/2016
University of Tirana — Tirana, Albania Bachelor of Science in Finance and Accounting	10/2011 - 07/2014

CERTIFICATES:

Accounting and Business Management, ACCA Global — London

Python - Coursera Certificate

01/2017–07/2023

01/2020

EXPERIENCE:

Institute of Modeling in Business — Tirana, Albania | Business Analyst

08/2016 - 04/2019

- Project manager to on-board clients in the new platform. Improved my team's performance by implementing about 30 new clients every 6 months.
- Proficient in managing full process flow of data analysis from collecting business requirement, data acquisition, Web scraping, data cleaning, features scaling, features engineering, data visualization & storytelling, data validation and predictive modeling.
- Hands-on experience of data cleaning, manipulating and analyzing large data set.
- Managed multiple projects simultaneously, leading work-flow analysis, build, training, on-site support, and go live site assessment. I got the opportunity to work with direct client engagements and finance teams to understand their business requirements and translate them into actionable insights.
- Collaborated with developers to design software customizations in accordance with client's business requirements. Excellent knowledge of SQL, Excel, Tableau and BI.
- Self-driven, solving technical problems and communicating clearly and effectively to technical and non-technical audiences.

Supreme State Audit — Tirana, Albania | Graduate Research Intern

01/2016 - 06/2016

- Demonstrated proficiency in accounting and auditing standards to produce clear and well-structured audit documentation. Worked in a team-based environment.
- Completed risk assessment procedures such as financial ration analysis and trend analysis.
- Prepared quarterly reviews: tying out balance sheet and income statement consolidations, preparing analyst expectation memos and attending test of controls walk-throughs.

SKILL-SETS:

- Programming/Languages: (Advanced)SQL, Python (Numpy, Pandas, matpoltlib, sci-kit, Tensor flow), R (dplyr, ggplot), MapReduce (AWS using S3, EC2).
- Strong analytical, creative and innovative approach to solving problems.
- Machine Learning Algorithms: Decision Tree, Regression, Classification, Clustering, Neural Network, Natural Language Processing (NLP), Sentiment Analysis, Topic modeling, Gensim, Image Classification, LSTM.
- Data Visualization: Tableau, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, BI, Excel.
- Statistical Techniques: Regression Analysis, Hypothesis Testing, A/B Testing
- Ability to multitask/manage competing priorities. Strong decision making and communication skills.

LANGUAGES SKILLS:

Albanian

Native or bilingual proficiency

English

Full professional proficiency

• Italian

Tuli professional proficiency

• Spanish Limited working proficiency

Professional working proficiency